Finding aid for the John Fahey papers LSC.1862
UCLA Library Special Collections
John Fahey papers
circa 1970-2009
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1862
24 Linear Feet (58 boxes)
John L. Fahey can be considered one of the founding fathers of the field of clinical immunology and was the founding president of the Clinical Immunology Society in 1986. He discovered Immunoglobulin D (IgD) while at NIH and delineated other classes of immunoglobulins. Throughout his career, he engaged in international education and training in immunology, building research capacity for HIV/AIDS in developing countries. One of his major contributions in the fight against AIDS has been his research in the interaction of the immune system and the nervous system, pointing out the complexity of the disease. Fahey helped to establish several UCLA Institutes, such as the NIH-funded Center for Interdisciplinary Research in Immunology and Disease (CIRID), initiated in 1978. The Fahey collection spans the period 1970 to 2009 and consists primarily of correspondence relating to grant applicants and applicants, research programs, Immunology conferences, between colleagues and researchers in the field, and national and international HIV/AIDS research. Much of the collection relates to programs and ties with India, and there are several grant applications, biographical sketches and various program outlines.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Fahey, 2010.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9966032163606533
Biography/History
Dr. John L. Fahey, born September 8, 1924, is an immunologist, researcher, and educator. He received his MS in Physiology at Wayne State Medical School in Detroit, 1949, and his MD at Harvard Medical School in Boston, 1951. Fahey received medical training and research experience at Wayne College of Medicine in Detroit, Harvard Medical School and other research centers in Europe in the 1940s and 1950s. As a Senior Investigator for the United States Public Health Service at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) from 1953-1959 he established the Clinical Research Laboratory and new methods for plasma protein analysis. While at the National Institutes of Health in the late 1970s, he discovered Immunoglobulin D (IgD), delineated and characterized the important classes of human immunoglobulins and established an Immunology Branch in NCI. At UCLA in the 1980s, he generated a community of clinical and laboratory scientists focusing on the role of the immune system, which led to the discovery of AIDS at UCLA.
Dr. Fahey can be considered one of the founding fathers of the field of clinical immunology and was the founding president of the Clinical Immunology Society in 1986. Much of Fahey's work has been gathering phenomenological data about disease process and correlating it to alterations in pathogenesis. Throughout his career, especially in the 1990's and the first decade of the 21st century, he engaged in international education and training in immunology and built research capacity for HIV/AIDS in developing countries. Nicholson was responsible for several interdisciplinary clinical and basic science training grants to UCLA and helped foster the subspecialty of clinical immunology in the Journal of Immunology.
Fahey became Chair of the Department of Microbiology and Immunology (later Microbiology, Immunology and Molecular Genetics) at UCLA in 1971, with a joint appointment the Department of Medicine; he became Director at the UCLA Advanced AIDS International Training and Research Program/India; Director, Center for International Research in Immunology and Disease at UCLA; Program Area Co-Director, AIDS in India Program, UCLA AIDS Institute; Head of the Tumor Immunology Program Area at the Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center (UCLA), Director at the Center for Interdisciplinary Research in Immunology and Disease (CIRID) at UCLA and Associate director for the UCLA AIDS Institute. John Fahey was one a leading, having published over 400 articles related to Immunology and AIDS research, and mentored more than 70 national and International postdoctoral scientists in biomedical research.
Scope and Content
The John L. Fahey collection spans the period 1970 to 2009, consisting primarily of correspondence about grant programs, between colleagues and researchers in Immunology, about Immunology conferences, and national and international HIV/AIDS research. Fahey helped to establish several UCLA Institutes, such as the NIH-funded Center for Interdisciplinary Research in Immunology and Disease (CIRID), initiated in 1978. CIRID focuses on research and capacity-building educational programs with India, thus the majority of the collection includes correspondence with Indian colleagues and researchers. Correspondence discusses programs and ties with the All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) and the Indian Department of Biotechnology (DBT).
Fahey also helped establish the UCLA/Fogarty AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) in 1988, with the objective of training health professionals from developing countries in multidisciplinary research for prevention of HIV infection, transmission and disease progression, and effective clinical management of HIV-infected individuals. Some correspondence thus relates to other developing nations in Asia, Africa and Latin America. The collection includes many grant applications, biographical sketches and correspondence of Fogarty recipients, as well as program details. Other institutes referenced in the collection are the UCLA Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, UCLA AIDS Institute/Center for AIDS Research, UCLA Clinical Immunology Research Laboratory (CIRL), the Concern Foundation and the International Union of Immunological Societies. In addition, there is extensive correspondence relating to Fahey's international travel for conferences and other HIV/AIDS research programs.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Funding Agencies
Training Manuals
International Travel
India
UCLA Institutes
International Societies and Correspondence.
Related Material
AIDS History Project collection, Coll2007-015. Available at the ONE National Gay and Lesbian Archives, Los Angeles, California.
Fahey, John L.--Archives.
- 1. Funding Agencies, 1983-2009
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, program outlines, grant applications, biographical sketches of scholars and other documentation related to agencies that funded HIV/AIDS research. The UCLA Fogarty program attracted and aided scholars from around the world, primarily from India, to work on AIDS in developing nations. Also included are documents and correspondence related to UCLA specific programs and committees working on immunological research.
  - Fogarty -- India, Tina Wu, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes audio cassette tape of speakers and photograph copy of negatives
  - Fogarty -- Department of Biotechnology, UNESCO Center, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty -- Deepika Khakha, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fogarty -- India, Sanjeev Sinha, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fogarty -- India, Baseline HIV Drug Resistance, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fogarty -- India, Sanjeev Sinha, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fogarty -- India, K.K. Ganguly, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fogarty -- India, Hari Kesh Sharma, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fogarty -- India, Subbian Arunkumar, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fogarty -- India, AIDS International Training and Research Program, general academic information, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fogarty -- India, Tanvir Kaur, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fogarty -- India, Tarun Bhatnagar, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fogarty -- India, Ajoy Roychoudhury, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Fogarty -- India, Arumugam Balamurugan, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fogarty -- India, Harpeet Sandhu, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fogarty -- India, Swapan Kumar Dey, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fogarty -- India, Narayanam Srikanth, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fogarty -- India, Sheik Iliayas, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fogarty -- India, Anju Dhawan, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fogarty -- India, Beena Thomas, 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty -- India, Hemraj Pal, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fogarty -- India, Kanchan Mukherjee, 2003-2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fogarty -- India, Mohanarani Suhadev, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fogarty -- India, Sushil Kabra, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fogarty -- India, Sreevatsa, ca. 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fogarty -- India, VVSP Prasad, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fogarty -- India, Lalit Dar, 1998-2009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fogarty -- India, biographical sketches, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fogarty -- India, trainee program, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fogarty -- correspondence regarding various research programs sponsored or affiliated with Fogarty, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fogarty -- correspondence and tables regarding research programs and AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) participants, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fogarty -- AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) progress report, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fogarty -- India, AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) scholars, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Fogarty --AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) program information, correspondence regarding awards, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Fogarty -- general tax information, staff and organization flow chart, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Fogarty -- international trainees, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fogarty -- Budgets, progress reports, supplement funds requests, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fogarty -- Grant applications and submissions for AIDS International Training & Research Program, New Delhi and Chennai, India, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty -- Application for continuation grant, progress report, trainees, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fogarty -- Program fellows, 1988-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fogarty -- Final Progress Report and Final Invention Statement and Certification, list of postdoctoral trainees, letters of intent for program, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fogarty -- Project report summary, list of collaborators and trainees, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fogarty -- Malignancy in AIDS research grant documentation and correspondence, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fogarty -- Lists of fellows prior to year 10, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fogarty -- Trainees, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fogarty -- Fellows, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fogarty -- India, Armed Forces Medical Services, India, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fogarty -- India, Radha Maheshwari, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fogarty -- Maj MP Cariappa, Armed Forces Medical Services, India, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fogarty -- India, Armed Forces Medical Services nominations for trainees, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fogarty -- General Janak Bhardwaj, Armed Forces Medical Service and Participant in Fogarty program, 2002-2009 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fogarty -- Sashindran Vangal Krishnaswamy, chloroquine therapy in HIV/AIDS research, 2004-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fogarty -- Mozambique, AIDS Control Within a Research Endeavor application and critique, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty -- Angola, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fogarty -- Mozambique, Aurelio de Cruz Gomes, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fogarty -- Supplement for research in India, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fogarty -- Shankar Subramanian, research on antiviral regimes, lecture on treatments, 2003-2009 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fogarty -- Ketoki Kapila, HIV and Tuberculosis research grants application and correspondence, 2002-2009 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fogarty -- Rajiv Gupta, 2003-2009 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fogarty -- Palat Menon, 2003-2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fogarty -- Ajay Sahni, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fogarty -- General Bhardwaj, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fogarty -- Armed Forces Medical College, Pune, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fogarty -- AIDS International Training and Research Program, Trainees, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fogarty -- Human Subjects Protection Committee (HSPC), AIDS International Training and Research Program, North India Supplement, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fogarty -- AIDS International Training and Research Program, India Survey, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty -- International program and course information, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Quality Assessment and Standardization for Immunological Measures Relevant to HIV/AIDS (QASI) -- correspondence and general information, 2003-2009 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Quality Assessment and Standardization for Immunological Measures Relevant to HIV/AIDS (QASI) -- Frank Mandy, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fogarty -- Joaquin Gomes A. Gonga, Angola, ca. 2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fogarty -- Filomena Burity Neto, Angola, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- Human Subjects Protection Committee, certification and review, 2002-2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Grants -- Application and Institutional Review Board correspondence for "Research on CME Programs for AIDS Treatment in India", 2005-2008 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Grants -- Institutional Review Board review of research on HIV and Tuberculosis at the Tuberculosis Research Centre, Chennai, India, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Grants -- Human Subjects Protection Committee, Peter Newman, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Grants -- Institutional Review Board review of "Feasibility of Rapid, In-clinic HIV Diagnostic Testing in Chennai, India", 2002 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Grants -- Human Subjects Protection Committee renewal for "AIDS Prevention with Traditional Systems of Medicine", 2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Grants -- Human Subjects Protection Committee, General Information, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Grants -- Grantsmanship, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Grants -- Center for AIDS Research (CFAR), International Core, 2003-2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Grants -- Center for AIDS Research (CFAR), International Core, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Grants -- World AIDS Foundation for "Delivery of Model HIV Prevention and Health Promotion Programs in India by Homeopathy Physicians and Educators", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Grants -- Fogarty proposal, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Grants -- All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) Supplement for International Clinical, Operational, and Health Services Research Training Award for AIDS and Tuberculosis (ICOHRTA-AIDS/TB), 2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Grants -- Fogarty, north India and China, 2003-2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- UCLA Fogarty AITRP-Supplement to North India, 2003-2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Grants -- Roger Detels, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Grants -- NIH Office of AIDS Research grant for National Training Program for Physicians in Clinical Management of AIDS in India, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Grants -- Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections, Pediatrics, 2004-2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Grants -- Indo-US CME (Continuing Medical Education) on Antiretroviral Treatment in HIV/AIDS, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Grants -- Continuing Medical Education (CME) programs budget and grant application, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Grants -- Continuing Medical Education materials, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Grants -- Continuing Medical Education, nurses, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Grants -- 2nd Indo-US CME on Antiretroviral Treatment in HIV/AIDS, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Grants -- 1st Indo-US CME (Continuing Medical Education) on Antiretroviral Treatment in HIV/AIDS, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Grants -- OAR (Office of AIDS Research)/NIH for CME, application and budget, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Grants -- Fogarty Global Health Framework, Gail Harrison, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Grants -- Seed grant and additional Funds for Continuing Medical Education research, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Grants -- HIV/AIDS Immunology Research in India conference, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Grants -- HIV/AIDS-Immunology Research in India program and conference, financial information, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Grants -- Office of AIDS Research correspondence regarding Immunology Research in India conference, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Grants -- UCLA Clinical and Translational Science Institute, Research Education, Training and Career Development (CTSI-ED), 2007 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- Cooperative Asthma, Allergy and Immunologic Disease Research, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Grants -- National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (AI), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Grants -- National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (AI), 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Grants -- National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (AI), proposal, budget, financial status report, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Grants -- National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (AI), Final Progress Report, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Grants -- National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (AI), 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Grants -- Concern Foundation, applications and correspondence regarding research on tumors and immune response systems, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Grants -- Concern Foundation, general information and correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Grants -- Concern Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Grants -- UCLA Tumor Immunology Training Program, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Grants -- UCLA Tumor Immunology Training Program, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Space Review, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Factor building space review, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Flow Cytometry Core Laboratory, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Flow Cytometer Facilities, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, control programs, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Bonavida special Fund, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Factor building space, 1983-1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Core grant, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Strategic Plan, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, space review, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Flow Cytometry Research Core Facility review, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, space review, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, space review and applications, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, program areas and correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, space review, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, general news, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Factor building space room survey, space changes, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Core grant, membership renewal, program announcements, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Grants -- Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, Strategic Plan, 1990 January 19 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 2. International Travel, 1983-2001
  This series contains travel documentation, correspondence, budgets and conference information for travel done by Fahey around the world. The documents relate to conferences on Immunology, HIV/AIDS and cancer, as well as medical training programs.
  - 2nd African Immunology Conference, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2nd African Congress, Nairobi meeting, 1994 October 23-27 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - India, 1994 March (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Chile, Brazil, 1993 April (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Washington DC, 1995 May 21-25 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - China, 1995 June (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Russia, 1995 May 30 - June 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - China, Advanced Immunological Course, 1996 October 21-28 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Spain, 3rd International Symposium of AIDS, 1996 October 28-29 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Mexico, 4th Latin American Congress of Immunology, 1996 March 3-7 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Turkey, Immunohabilitation, 1996 May 5-10 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - South Africa, Federation of African Immunological Societies (FAIS), 1997 March 10-14 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Amsterdam, 13th European Immunology Meeting, 1997 June 22-25 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Amsterdam, Fourth International Symposium on Clinical Immunology, 1997 June 19-22 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Peru, XI Latin American Congress on Sexually Transmitted Diseases, 1997 December 3-6 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Philippines, 4th International Congress on AIDS in Asia and the Pacific, 1997 October 25-29 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Guangzhou, China and Hong Kong, 1998 October 28 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - India, China, Geneva, itineraries, 1998 March (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Geneva, XII International AIDS Conference, 1998 June 28 - July 3 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - India, 10th International Congress of Immunology, 1998 November 1-7 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Uruguay, V Latin American Congress of Immunology, 1999 December 12-16 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - India, 2000 October-November (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - New Delhi, India, 2000 January 27-29 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Chennai, India, 2000 January 11-13 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Chennai, India, 5th International Conference on Emerging Infectious Diseases in the Pacific Rim, 2000 January 7-9 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cameroon, Fourth International Conference of the Federation of African Immunology Societies, 2000 February 14-17 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Thailand, Federation of Immunological Societies of Asia-Oceania, 2000 January 23 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Brazil, correspondence regarding UNAIDS, developing a research center, cytometry labs, and HIV/AIDS research and workshops, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Brazil, immunological articles and research group information, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Brazil, proposal for World AIDS Foundation, correspondence, research information, 1994-1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Chile, correspondence, III Congress of the Latin American Association of Immunology, correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Russia, correspondence regarding AIDS research, 1988-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - England, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - France, correspondence regarding an international immunology meeting, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Iceland, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Italy, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Portugal, Immunological Society meeting, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Mexico, correspondence regarding meetings and educational programs in Mexico, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Poland, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Washington DC, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Kenya, 1990 July 16-August 7 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Africa, general information on AIDS in Africa and correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Egypt, International Course for Clinical Immunology, 1997-1999 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - China, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - China, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 16)